# Manuel Sabin, Ph.D.

San Francisco, CA | (916) 496-6413

msabin.github.io
msabin27@gmail.com

## **Career Highlights**

**Impact:** Published first provably secure Proofs of Work. Contributed security-critical features to the Go standard library. Published in top Crypto, CS Theory, and ML conferences (ALT, CRYPTO, STOC) with  $\sim$ 375 citations.

**Leadership:** Organized workshops ( $\sim$ 800 attendees) and served on panels and publishing committees at premiere ML venues (CVPR, FAccT\*, ICML, NeurIPS). Secured  $\sim$ \$160K grant for Cryptography research.

**Communication:** Invited to present my work at 20+ venues (e.g. MIT, Stanford, UC Berkeley). Interviewed by media outlets (e.g. MIT Tech Review, Nature, & was a prominently featured expert in Simons Institute short film).

### **Experience**

#### Lycalopex Fellowship, Software Engineering Fellow

Jun 2024 - Jul 2024

Competitive paid fellowship to contribute to the official Go cryptography library

- Created the new cryptotest package introducing reusable testing suites for Go's crypto library
- Authored a testing suite for each interface of Go's core secret-key primitives in 5 weeks, spanning 60+ tests
- · Caught a security bug in the CTR mode stream cipher that my tests uncovered and filed an issue

#### Recurse Center, Software Engineer in Residence

Aug 2023 - Oct 2023

Sabbatical at programmer's retreat centering collaboration, pair programming, and self-driven projects

- Built interactive DSP web apps with React and WebMIDI/WebSockets and music software with Python
- · Initiated & led weekly workshops on dev tooling, web accessibility, and ran sprints for bite-sized web projects
- Wrote & presented lecture series on math in music software: geometric intuitions of the Fourier transform

#### **EduExplora, Instructor and Program Creator**

May 2023 - Jul 2020

UC Berkeley STEM outreach program for exceptional international high school students from Latin America

- · Created & taught an Introductory Python course on Object-Oriented design and physics simulations
- · Coached 30 student developers on utilizing documentation, debugging, and pair programming

#### Radboud and VUB Universities, ML Consultant and Researcher

May 2020 - Jan 2021

Consulted on modern ML-based Legal Tech for competitive ERC-funded COHUBICOL Project

- Surveyed existing Legal Tech and documented a vocabulary of technical concepts at the intersection of ML and Law, improving legibility and testability of these technologies for lawyers and legal philosophers
- Trained a team of lawyers on fundamental ML topics and mentored a CS PhD student

#### Education

**UC Berkeley, PhD Computer Science** 

Aug 2020

CSU Sacramento, BA Math & CS; Minor in Statistics (Commencement Speaker)

May 2014

## Skills

C, C++, CSS, Go, HTML, Java, JavaScript, JSX, MATLAB, MySQL, Python, R, Sass, Scheme, TypeScript Express.js, git, Linux, Node.js, React.js, socket.io, Unix, WebAudio, WebMIDI, WebSocket